Guide to the M. Stanford Jackson Papers, 1873-1916 DAR.1996.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
M. Stanford Jackson Papers
1873-1916
1888-1890
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jackson, M. Stanford
DAR.1996.01
0.21 Linear Feet (1 box)
Upon his father's death in 1889, M. Stanford Jackson took over the daily operations and management of the Idlewood Hotel and Cottages (formerly the Jackson family's Greenwood home). This collection consists of correspondence to M. Stanford Jackson, receipts and one ledger possibly in connection the Idlewood Hotel. Several souvenirs/advertising brochures for the Idlewood, as well as calling cards, birth announcements, daily menu plans and other miscellaneous items are also present.
Biography
Morange Stanford Jackson, son of William Stanford Jackson (1829-1889) and Katherine A. Morange, was born in 1860. M. Stanford Jackson had two brothers, Shirls (born in 1870) and Chevalier (1865-1958). Upon his father's death on Christmas holiday in 1889, M. Stanford Jackson took over the daily operations and management of the Idlewood Hotel and Cottages (formerly the Jackson family's Greenwood home).
Scope and Content Notes
This collection consists of correspondence to M. Stanford Jackson (mostly from family members), receipts and one ledger possibly in connection the Idlewood Hotel, several souvenirs/advertising brochures for the Idlewood, as well as calling cards, birth announcements, daily menu plans and other miscellaneous items.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Darlington Memorial Library acquired the papers from Carmen D. Valentino on August 9, 1996.
Custodial History
This collection was located in the Darlington Memorial Library in the University's Cathedral of Learning until 2007 when it was moved to the ULS Archives Service Center for processing, storage, preservation and service. However, it remains in the custodianship of the ULS Special Collections Department.
Previous Citation
M. Stanford Jackson Papers, 1873-1916, DAR.1996.01, Darlington Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
This collection has been previously cited as DAR# 3.
Correspondence; Ledgers (Account books); Account books; Hotels -- Pennsylvania -- Idlewood; Idlewood (Pa.) -- Social life and customs; Jackson, M. Stanford; Workingman's Mutual Savings Bank (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Idlewood Hotel and Cottages (Idlewood, Pa.)
- Account Ledger, September 1879-July 1880 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, to Cousin Stanford (Sarah Sweeney), January 1888-February 1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, to Dear Cousin (Cousin Sadie), October 26, 1888-March 11, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, to My Dear Cousin (Lydie Simone), July 1888-December 1889 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, to Stanford (W.E. Smith), August 1888-May 1894 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, to Stanford Jackson (Martha Quincy), March 1895 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1885-1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Idlewood Hotel (Miscellaneous Items), 1884, 1890-1891 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous (Personal Items), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Notary Public Protest, November 24, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Receipts, 1881-1916 (Box 1, Folder 11)